LATA SHARAN

+91 9456044670 ♦ Indra Nagar, Aligarh, UP, India

sharanlata132@gmail.com \$\display \text{https://www.linkedin.com/in/lata-sharan-6b283b207/} \$\display \text{https://github.com/Lata-Sharan}\$

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer with 1+ years of experience in Data Analysis, writing Test Cases for Automotive Functions and HIL Manual and Automation Testing along with writing python scripts for new ECU architecture. Parallel to that, I am pursuing Post Graduate Programme in Data Science and Machine Learning from Intellipat, seeking full-time Data Analyst or Data Scientist roles.

EDUCATION

PGP in Data Science and Machine Learning, Intellipat

September 2023 - Present

MySQL

Python Basics and OOPS Concept

Inferential Statistics

Numpy, Pandas, Machine Learning

BSc Hons. (Computer Applications), Aligarh Muslim University

August 2019- July 2022

Seminar Paper Presentation: CNN (Convolutional Neural Networks) Major Project: Drowsiness Detection System

Minor Project: Hostel Management Website[Teamwork]

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS: MySQL, Python, Data Analysis, Git, Microsoft Office, OpenCV, Vector CANAPE, dSPACE, Tensorflow, SkLearn, Machine Learning, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Data Transformation

SOFT SKILLS: Innovation, Adaptability, Teamwork, Creativity, Analytical Thinking, Multi Tasking, issue resolution, Planning and Delivery, Fluent Communication

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Nov 2022 - Present

Diensten Tech Ltd (Client Maruti Suzuki India Ltd)

Guruqram, Haryana

- Optimization of HILS Automation Script in python according to new Automotive ECU Architecture.
- HILS Automation Testcase Preparation for ECGW and EIU
- HILS Testing and Analysis (dSPACE Control/Automation Desk and Vector CANOE/CANAPE)
- Testing of Body Control Module Functions prepared by Suppliers
- Data Analysis on Time Series Data

Machine Learning Intern

1 June 2021 - 31 July 2021

Google Developer Students Club, AMU

AMU, India

- Deployed Used-Car-Price Prediction Model on Heroku App using FastAPI and ML algorithms.
- Algorithm Used: Linear Regression, SVR(Support Vector Regression), KNN(K-Nearest Neighbour), Decision Tree, Random Forest.

PROJECTS

Drowsiness Detection System This system was trained over 84000 images. It raise an alarm if drowsiness is detected. Different modules and python libraries were used for Data Preparation. Then model was trained on Transfer Learning Approach using Inception V3 and ResNet-50 CNN architectures. Later, the trained model was validated using Haarcascade Classifier, and OpenCV (Github Link)

Unsupervised Machine Learning Projects Worked on 2 projects related to Unsupervised Learning: Credit card Clustering and College Reports data. In these projects, I preprocessed data using Standard Scaler and PCA. Then, used K Means, Agglomerative, DBSCAN clustering to get the highest Silhouette value and better accuracy(Github Link)

Supervised Machine Learning Projects Worked on 2 projects related to Supervised Learning: Insurance(Linear Regression) and Soccer Fever(Logistic Regression). In these projects algorithms used are Linear Regression, Ridge, Lasso, AdaBoost, SVM, KNeighbor Classifier, Decision Tree, Random Forest to get better accuracy(Github Link)

HONOURS AND CERTIFICATES

- HACKER RANK PROBLEM SOLVING Silver badge(4 Star) https://www.hackerrank.com/sharanlata132
- LEETCODE SQL 50 Badge https://leetcode.com/Sharanlata/
- SDS BIT Mesra ML Contest 21st rank in 126 on Public Leaderboard
- MISS TALENTED 2017 Certificate Of Honour
- ENGLISH ACCESS MICROSCHOLARSHIP PROGRAM (2014-2015)sponsored by US Embassy Certificate Of Completion

LEADERSHIP

- Kabaddi captain (2018-2019)
- Secretary Hindi Society (2016-2017)